Alice Richardson

Lady Lake, Florida | 970-817-1904 | Alice.richardson.dev@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub | Blog

SUMMARY

I am a Frontend Developer with extensive experience and a bachelor's degree in design. I have completed the Full Stack Development Immersive Program from Flatiron school. I have a keen eye for the visual aspect of user experience and a strong desire to learn and create. I firmly believe in lifelong learning, and I'm constantly exploring new ideas and technologies. Having experience in both design and development, I am confident in my ability to create the most optimal user experiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Vue, React Native, Bootstrap, Material-UI, Node, Express, Ruby on Rails, MongoDB,

GENERAL SKILLS / API INTEGRATION

UX and UI Design, Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator, Public API, Git, Github, Customer Service

WORK EXPERIENCE

Chim Media | Frontend Engineer | UX & UI Designer

Feb 2021 - Present

- -Design frontend webpage, integrate with public API
- -Working with in a team developing frontend, backend, and UX / UI
- -Working in Agile environment

Full Stack Developer | Flatiron School

Jan 2020 - May 2020

- -Design website from backend to frontend.
- -Work with public API and create own API, also deploy the application on Heroku, Firebase

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Ecofreak // Vue | Node | Express | MongoDB - Github | Demo

Web application to inspire environmentally safe practices, and learn how to lessen one's environmental footprint

- Created and styled frontend with Vue and Material design for bootstrap
- Built collaborative blog interface for users to share and contribute ideas to better help the world
- Created own API to allow users to save directly to a database

Parking Spot Finder // React-native | Ruby | Rails | AsyncStorage - Github | Demo

Mobile application to help users find a parking spot near their current location or destination

- Created a secure login using JSON web Tokens and AsyncStorage
- Enabled seamless mobile iOS and Android UX via React Native and Expo
- Integrated Google Maps API and Google Places API to locate users by longitude and latitude

Thai Alphabet Flashcards // HTML | CSS | Javascript | Ruby | Rails - Github | Demo

Web application helps learning Thai language, with a mix-and-match game

- Made a mix-and-match memorization game with a time limit and dynamic scoring using Javascript
- Designed clean and simple UI/UX for a focused learning experience
- Included audible readouts of letters to aid the visual impair

Coffee Shop // HTML | CSS | Javascript | Ruby | Rails - Github | Demo

Web application to help coffee shop owners keep track of their stock

- Built Full CRUD backend with Ruby on Rails
- Used Javascript, HTML and CSS to style
- Manipulated and set the HTML content of an element using DOM

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

- Speaker at Women Who Code Boulder/Denver Monthly Meetup Video

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Jan 2020 - May 2020 | Denver, CO

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, and JavaScript Immersive Program **Bangkok University**